RG 004:104, Norwich Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Norwich Probate Court records
1748-1965
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Norwich District)
115.25 cubic feet
Record books, 1748-1965; Probate files, 1748-1896.
RG004_104
1914-007 and 2011-062
Historical Note
Norwich, New London County, Town settled 1659, established in May 1662, City incorporated May 1784
The Norwich Probate District was constituted October, 1748, from the New London Probate District. The Norwich Probate District serves the municipalities of Bozrah, Franklin, Griswold, Lisbon, Norwich, Preston, Sprague, and Voluntown.
City of Norwich, Probate District chronology:
1660 - May 1666, Particular Court Jurisdiction at Hartford, later at New London
May 1666 - October 1748, New London District
October 1748 - Present, Norwich District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, 1748-1965. Contact the probate court to access record books not listed below. Volumes titled "Journal" record the proceedings of the court. Volumes titled "Estates" are orders and decrees.See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1748-1896. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1748-1896 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books are numbered separately within the following: Journals; Records; Estates; Assigned estates; Guardians, conservators, etc.; Bonds.
Probate files in accession 1914-007 are arranged alphabetically.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1914-007 are represented in this index.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Bozrah; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Franklin; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Griswold; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Lisbon; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Norwich; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Preston; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Sprague; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Voluntown
Places:
Bozrah (Conn.); Franklin (Conn.); Griswold (Conn.); Lisbon(Conn.); Norwich (Conn.); Preston (Conn.); Sprague (Conn.); Voluntown (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
The following volumes are RESTRICTED due to condition: Journals, all volumes except 6 and 19; Records, 2, 7-43; Estates, 1-16; Guardians, conservators, etc., 4. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
Accession 2011-062, Record books, 1748-1965, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1-72, 1748-1917 and journals, volumes 1-17 except volume 2, 1748-1852, probate files, 1748-1880; and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the. The journals on microfilm are titled "Administrations (daily blotters)".
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1914-007 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): May 5, 1914 (1748-1896).
The record books in accession 2011-062 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on November 30, 2010 and December 13, 2010.
Container List
- Record books, 1748-1965; 81 cubic feet (154 volumes); 2011-062
  See Restrictions on Access note above
  - Journal, 1748-1763 (Volume 1)
  - Journal, 1763-1773 (Volume 2)
    Journal, Volume 2 does not exist as a separate item. Years 1763-1770 is bound with Records, Volume 3 and years 1770-1773 is bound with Records, Volume 4. This appears to have been done when these volumes received conservation treatment and were rebound.
  - Journal, 1774-1783 (Volume 3)
  - Journal, 1783-1793 (Volume 4)
  - Journal, 1793-1802 (Volume 5)
  - Journal, 1802-1811 (Volume 6)
  - Journal, 1811-1816 (Volume 7)
  - Journal, 1816-1820 (Volume 8)
  - Journal, 1820-1825 (Volume 9)
  - Journal, 1825-1829 (Volume 10)
  - Journal, 1829-1833 (Volume 11)
  - Journal, 1833-1836 (Volume 12)
  - Journal, 1836-1841 (Volume 13)
  - Journal, 1841-1844 (Volume 14)
  - Journal, 1844-1848 (Volume 15)
  - Journal, 1848-1850 (Volume 16)
  - Journal, 1850-1852 (Volume 17)
  - Journal, 1852-1855 (Volume 18)
  - Journal, 1855-1865 (Volume 19)
  - Records, 1748-1761 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1761-1763 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1764-1768 (Volume 3)
    Part of Journal, Volume 2 is bound in reverse with Records, Volume 3
  - Records, 1769-1773 (Volume 4)
    Part of Journal, Volume 2 is bound in reverse with Records, Volume 4
  - Records, 1773-1776 (Volume 5)
  - Records, 1776-1780 (Volume 6)
  - Records, 1780-1787 (Volume 7)
  - Records, 1787-1793 (Volume 8)
  - Records, 1787-1797 (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1795-1807 (Volume 10)
  - Records, 1806-1811 (Volume 11)
  - Records, 1811-1818 (Volume 12)
  - Records, 1818-1826 (Volume 13)
  - Records, 1826-1832 (Volume 14)
  - Records, 1832-1837 (Volume 15)
  - Records, 1837-1842 (Volume 16)
  - Records, 1842-1847 (Volume 17)
  - Records, 1847-1849 (Volume 18)
  - Records, 1849-1852 (Volume 19)
  - Records, 1852-1855 (Volume 20)
  - Records, 1855-1858 (Volume 21)
  - Records, 1858-1861 (Volume 22)
  - Records, 1861-1863 (Volume 23)
  - Records, 1863-1865 (Volume 24)
  - Records, 1865-1867 (Volume 25)
  - Records, 1867-1870 (Volume 26)
  - Records, 1870-1872 (Volume 27)
  - Records, 1872-1873 (Volume 28)
  - Records, 1873-1874 (Volume 29)
  - Records, 1875-1876 (Volume 30)
  - Records, 1876-1878 (Volume 31)
  - Records, 1878-1880 (Volume 32)
  - Records, 1880-1883 (Volume 33)
  - Records, 1882-1885 (Volume 34)
  - Records, 1885-1886 (Volume 35)
  - Records, 1886-1888 (Volume 36)
  - Records, 1888 (Volume 37)
  - Records, 1889-1890 (Volume 38)
  - Records, 1890-1891 (Volume 39)
  - Records, 1891-1892 (Volume 40)
  - Records, 1892 (Volume 41)
  - Records, 1893 (Volume 42)
  - Records, 1893-1894 (Volume 43)
  - Records, 1893-1895 (Volume 44)
  - Records, 1895 (Volume 45)
  - Records, 1895-1896 (Volume 46)
  - Records, 1896-1897 (Volume 47)
  - Records, 1897-1898 (Volume 48)
  - Records, 1898 (Volume 49)
  - Records, 1899-1900 (Volume 50)
  - Records, 1900 (Volume 51)
  - Records, 1900-1901 (Volume 52)
  - Records, 1901-1902 (Volume 53)
  - Records, 1902-1903 (Volume 54)
  - Records, 1903-1904 (Volume 55)
  - Records, 1904 (Volume 56)
  - Records, 1904-1905 (Volume 57)
  - Records, 1905-1906 (Volume 58)
  - Records, 1905-1906 (Volume 59)
  - Records, 1906-1907 (Volume 60)
  - Records, 1907 (Volume 61)
  - Records, 1907-1908 (Volume 62)
  - Records, 1909-1910 (Volume 63)
  - Records, 1910 (Volume 64)
  - Records, 1910-1911 (Volume 65)
  - Records, 1911-1912 (Volume 66)
  - Records, 1912-1913 (Volume 67)
  - Records, 1913-1914 (Volume 68)
  - Records, 1914 (Volume 69)
  - Records, 1914-1915 (Volume 70)
  - Records, 1915-1916 (Volume 71)
  - Records, 1916-1917 (Volume 72)
  - Records, 1917-1918 (Volume 73)
  - Records, 1918-1919 (Volume 74)
  - Records, 1919-1920 (Volume 75)
  - Records, 1920-1922 (Volume 76)
  - Estates, 1857-1860 (Volume 1)
  - Estates, 1860-1863 (Volume 2)
  - Estates, 1864-1870 (Volume 3)
  - Estates, 1870-1873, 1913 (Volume 4)
  - Estates, 1872-1879 (Volume 5)
  - Estates, 1875-1897 (Volume 6)
  - Estates, 1881-1893 (Volume 7)
  - Estates, 1885-1888 (Volume 8)
  - Estates, 1887-1893 (Volume 9)
  - Estates, 1890-1920 (Volume 10)
  - Estates, 1897-1898 (Volume 11)
  - Estates, 1894-1913 (Volume 12)
  - Estates, 1895-1913 (Volume 13)
  - Estates, 1897-1898 (Volume 14)
  - Estates, 1897-1901 (Volume 15)
  - Estates, 1897-1940 (Volume 16)
  - Estates, 1897-1913, 1965 (Volume 17)
  - Estates, 1812-1933 (Volume 17A)
  - Estates, 1899-1900 (Volume 18)
  - Estates, 1900-1902 (Volume 19)
  - Estates, 1901-1904 (Volume 20)
  - Estates, 1903-1904 (Volume 21)
  - Estates, 1904-1906 (Volume 22)
  - Estates, 1905-1907 (Volume 23)
  - Estates, 1906-1908 (Volume 24)
  - Estates, 1907-1909 (Volume 25)
  - Estates, 1909-1912 (Volume 26)
  - Estates, 1910-1912 (Volume 27)
  - Estates, 1911-1913 (Volume 28)
  - Estates, 1913-1914 (Volume 29)
  - Estates, 1914-1915 (Volume 30)
  - Estates, 1915-1916 (Volume 31)
  - Estates, 1916-1918 (Volume 32)
  - Estates, 1917-1918 (Volume 33)
  - Estates, 1918-1919 (Volume 34)
  - Estates, 1919-1920 (Volume 35)
  - Estates, 1920-1921 (Volume 36)
  - Assigned estates, 1875-1885 (Volume 1)
  - Assigned estates, 1885-1907 (Volume 2)
  - Guardians and wards, 1858-1871 (Volume 1)
  - Guardians and wards, 1871-1895 (Volume 2)
  - Guardians and wards, 1879-1886 (Volume 3)
  - Guardians & wards, conservators, trustees & insane, 1887-1893 (Volume 4)
  - Guardians, conservators, insane, etc., 1898-1905 (Volume 5)
  - Guardians, conservators, insane, etc., 1905-1911 (Volume 6)
  - Guardians, conservators, insane, etc., 1910-1919 (Volume 7)
  - Guardians, conservators, etc., 1919-1928 (Volume 8)
  - Bonds, 1883-1889 (Volume unnumbered)
  - Bonds, 1881-1883 (Volume 1)
  - Bonds, 1882-1891 (Volume 2)
  - Bonds, 1882-1892 (Volume 3)
  - Bonds, 1891-1897 (Volume 4)
  - Bonds, 1897-1903 (Volume 5)
  - Bonds, 1902-1906 (Volume 6)
  - Bonds, 1906-1910 (Volume 7)
  - Bonds, 1910-1912 (Volume 8)
  - Bonds, 1914-1918 (Volume 9)
  - Bonds, 1918-1921 (Volume 10)
  - Receipt book, 1910-1930 (Volume unnumbered)
  - Book of registrars, 1880-1940 (Volume unnumbered)
- Probate files, 1748-1896; 34.25 cubic feet; 1914-007
  - Abbe - Albro (Drawer 1)
  - Alden - Ayer (Drawer 2)
  - Babbage - Beach (Drawer 3)
  - Beard - Blackburn (Drawer 4)
  - Blackman - Brewster, J. (Drawer 5)
  - Brewster, K. - Burdick, J. (Drawer 6)
  - Burdick, K. - Carr (Drawer 7)
  - Carroll - Cocheat (Drawer 8)
  - Cochran - Crary, J. (Drawer 9)
  - Crary, K. - Downer (Drawer 10)
  - Crary, K. - Downer (Drawer 11)
  - Fitch, F. - Gates, S. (Drawer 12)
  - Gates, T. - Halisay (Drawer 13)
  - Hall - Hill, R. (Drawer 14)
  - Hill, S. - Huntington, I. (Drawer 15)
  - Huntington, J. - Johnson, M. (Drawer 16)
  - Johnson, N. - Ladd, B. (Drawer 17)
  - Ladd, C. - Lawton, J. (Drawer 18)
  - Lawton, K. - Loveland (Drawer 19)
  - Lovell - Meech (Drawer 20)
  - Meeker - Myers (Drawer 21)
  - Mygatt - Park, G. (Drawer 22)
  - Park, H. - Phillips, L. (Drawer 23)
  - Phillips, M. - Reynolds (Drawer 24)
  - Rhodes - Rude (Drawer 25)
  - Ruge - Smith, I. (Drawer 26)
  - Smith, J. - Story, I. (Drawer 27)
  - Story, J. - Tracy, I. (Drawer 28)
  - Tracy, J. - Tracy, S. (Drawer 29)
  - Tracy, T. - Trudeau (Drawer 30)
  - True - Tucker (Drawer 31)
  - Tufts - Tyler, John (Drawer 32)
  - Tyler, Joseph - Utley (Drawer 33)
  - Vail - Wales (Drawer 34)
  - Walker - Washburn (Drawer 35)
  - Waterman - Watrous (Drawer 36)
  - Watson - Weldon (Drawer 37)
  - Wells - Whipple, R. (Drawer 38)
  - Whipple, S. - Whiting, F. (Drawer 39)
  - Whiting, G. - Wilcox, I. (Drawer 40)
  - Wilcox, J. - Williams, G. (Drawer 41)
  - Williams, H. - Williams, M. (Drawer 42)
  - Williams, N. - Willoughby (Drawer 43)
  - Wilson - Witter, B. (Drawer 44)
  - Witter, C. - Woodburn (Drawer 45)
  - Woodmansee - Woolsey (Drawer 46)
  - Worden - Young, B. (Drawer 47)
  - Young, C. - Zundel (Drawer 48)
  - Miscellaneous Papers (Drawer 49)
- Inventory Control Book, 1748-1896; T003073
  Index of the four accessions of probate files now merged into accession 1914-007
  Date span is coverage
  Also known as the Godard Digest